here's 28 it has three steps very famous
my men taking refuge meditation number
one this side I've already went there
okay I already went there where lower
realms lower realms I'm in hell I'm an
animal I'm a hungry spirit decide you
already went there
okay what's the photograph this is a
famous photo that was taken during the
Vietnam War and these people are being
shot on right right at that moment
somebody's trying to kill them right at
that moment okay it's like a hell they
jump into the water they can't stay
under the water they have to put their
head up in that moment someone was a
real it's a real photo someone was
trying to kill them at that moment okay
and this guy took a photo and he
survived and it's just a normal family
there's a mom and there's the mom her
daughter grandma mom and kids and
someone's trying to kill them in this
moment of death photograph okay why are
we talking about that
imagine you're already in the hell
realms like you didn't take refuge very
well you spent the three days on your
cell phone so you went to places like
the other carry then your mind will
object your mind will say no no no I'm a
diamond mountain in a nice comfortable
beautiful cool retreat cottage because
of Melissa and Michael you know I'm anti
here I'm not in the hell nobody's
shooting at me okay then step number two
what's that I do have the seeds
okay if I died this afternoon I would go
to a place like that
okay so first part I am in the house
already then your mind will say no no no
no no I'm in retreat comes in Diamond
Mountain
it's hot as now but it's not how then
you then you have to look into your mind
you know do you have to see the knives
and then the answer is yes I have to see
I could go there if I died this
afternoon
you know if I'm the first person to die
from rattlesnake at Diamond Mountain
it's possible I could go there and then
third it's supposed to be happy thought
what's that
I have sheltered like a son a small boy
who who has dad he can hang on to dad
and say help me done okay who's that
Buddha Dharma Sangha okay I have I have
shelter I have refuge
I have protection I can hang on to my
dad okay like done okay all right
try to remember this photograph try to
memorize the photograph okay you can
give yourself a photo quiz look at the
photos and say what was I supposed to
meditate about okay and then you won't
forget the meditations you can do them
after you get home it's on the bus on
the airplane okay when your flights
delayed in the LA Airport or you're in
the LA customs line for two hours
don't waste your time who was that we
enig did the whole translator program
designed waiting in a customs lang where
Thailand
yeah Phuket 11 o'clock at night
something like that I don't remember
okay that's another meditation you can
do okay now if you want to get to the
first one conveniently what's the first
one of those three you're in the hell
and somebody shooting at you at cetera
okay do the meditation after it first
what's that
death meditation go through the stages
of death okay if it's if you have
difficult jumping into being shot at do
the death meditation before then you're
reviewing the last part of the lemon
this for reference you're reviewing that
one which is death meditation okay so
tie together retreat number 22 reaching
number 23 retreat number 24 and retreat
number 25 okay those of you who came to
them who's smart enough to come to them
tie them together you know try to
remember what came before and don't
don't let it go when you do the next one
room okay don't don't forget about death
meditation when you start refuge and
when you reach karma in Guadalajara
don't give up don't drop the refuse okay
like try to keep some continuity of the
lumber okay I get it